SUDHIR KAUSHIK, MBA, PMP®

@: Kaushik.nt@hotmail.com Mobile: +86-1525-150-9001

Nationality: Indian

PROJECT MANAGEMENT • STRATEGY CONSULTANT • L&D SPECIALIST



SUMMARY AND SKILLS

Sudhir **Kaushik** possesses 12-years' working experience with top MNCs and multicultural team. Kaushik is an avid learner and passionate towards following domains:

- Project Management
- Talent Development
- Agile Methodologies

- Java Development
- Business Communication
- Business Strategy

EXPERIENCE

Senior Consultant, Strategy Division, NTT DATA Corporation.

Wuxi, China

Dec 2013 ~ Now

- Developing RFPs response and deliver proposal presentation (ENG Only).
- PMO's (Project Management Office) activities.
- NTT DATA China's representative in APC (Agile Professional Center) Global Network.
- Promote agile culture in Organization.
- Conduct introductory Seminar on IOT, Cloud Computing.
- Oversee Employee engagement including program delivery.

Senior Trainer – IEB (International Education Business), NIIT Ltd.

Shanghai, China.

Oct 2007 ~ Dec 2013.

- Imparted IT training to undergraduate students in schools, colleges and universities in China.
- TOT (Training of Trainers) & Corporate Trainings.

Software Faculty → Academic Coordinator Titan & Softdot Technologies

New Delhi, India.

Apr 2004 ~ Oct 2007

PROJECT EXPERIENCE

1. Project Name: Shanghai Sports Stadium (Jan 2015 till Dec 2015)

[Click Here] to view this application.

Project Summary: Shanghai sports stadium's customer management system. System had 3 interfaces – PC, mobile devices (Android and iOS). System serve the following users-

- **Customer** shall book, cancel or modify the various slots at multiple facilities to play badminton, table tennis, volleyball, basketball etc.
- Administrator shall manage all activities like sales promotion, ticket management.
- Field Manager shall manage the particular field related services.

My Roles & Responsibilities:

- Active participation in requirement analysis and design creation.
- Developing web interface.
- Project executive manage WBS, meetings and project communication.

Technical Environment: Java framework, Spring, JSP, HTML5, JQuery, MySQL, Apache Tomcat etc.

2. Manage and Supervise Numerous Academic Projects during my tenure in NIIT China as Senior IT Trainer.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

- MBA (International Business) from SM University India.
- MCA from IGNOU New Delhi India.
- M.Sc. (Statistics) from CCS University India.
- B.Sc. (Mathematics, Statistics, Physics) from CCS University India.
- 45 professional development courses from ELEMENT K, USA (Now SKILLSOFT).

TECHNICAL SKILLS: Java related skills (Core Java, Spring, Hibernate), MySQL, HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery etc.

CERTIFICATIONS

- PMI-PMP®
- SCJP
- MCPD (WINDOWS, WEB)
- NCC 'B' & 'C' Certificate

AWARDS

- Best Leader Award NCC Annual Camp.
- Best Speaker Award (Chinese) NTT DATA.
- Best Presentation Award (Chinese) NTT DATA.

COMMUNITY SERVICE Administer Weekly English Corner activities in Wuxi District Library. **BILINGUAL (CH-ENG) BLOG [Click Here]**

LANGUAGE KNOWN: Hindi हिन्दी , English, Punjabi ਪੰਜਾਬੀ, Chinese 中文, Spanish español (Learning..)

LINKED-IN PROFILE [Click Here]
ONLINE COPY OF RESUME [Click Here]

[Sudhir Kaushik]

高兴 KAUSHIK, MBA, PMP®

@: Kaushik.nt@hotmail.com Mobile: +86-1525-150-9001

国籍:印度

PROJECT MANAGEMENT • STRATEGY CONSULTANT • L&D SPECIALIST

生涯概要:

高兴在 IT、业务培训、咨询以及项目管理方面拥有 12 年的学习发展经历。同时拥有以下领域的经验:

● 项目管理

Java 开发

● 人才发展

● 敏捷方法论

● 商务沟通

● 商业战略

经验:

高级顾问, 推进本部, NTT DATA 有限公司.

无锡,中国

2013.12~ 今日

- 撰写项目提案并负责提案的演讲(英语)
- PMO's (Project Management Office) activities.
- NTT DATA 中国的 APC(Agile Professional Center)负责代表
- 负责在公司内推广敏捷文化
- 处理物联网,云计算,大数据研讨会
- 审查员工敬业度,包括方案执行

高级培训师-IEB (International Education Business), NIIT Ltd. 2007.10~2013.12.

上海,中国.

- 给与应届毕业生 IT 培训
- 培训教师和企业培训

Software Faculty → Academic Coordinator Titan & Softdot Technologies

新德里,印度.

2004.04 ~ 2007.10

IT 项目经验

1. 项目: 场馆售票管理系统 [Click Here] 看这个系统。(1月 2015 到 12月 2015)

客户:上海体育馆

项目概要:上海体育馆场馆售票管理系统拥有三个接口-PC端,Android和iOS。系统有三种用户

- 用户可以注册,预定,取消,修改订单,比如:羽毛球,乒乓,篮球等等。
- 管理人可以管理所有的功能如:销售活动,票管理。
- 场馆可以管理各自场馆的服务。

我的角色与责任

- 参加需求分析和设计
- Project executive- 管理 WBS, 会议,项目沟通。

技术环境: Java 框架, Spring, JSP, HTML5, JQuery, MySQL, Apache Tomcat etc.

2. 管理和监督众多学术项目我的任期在 NIIT 中国高级 IT 培训期间。

资格与培训

- MBA (International Business) from SM 大学, 印度.
- MCA from IGNOU 新德里, 印度.
- M.Sc. (统计学) from CCS 大学, 印度.
- **B.Sc.** (数学, 物理学, 统计学) from CCS 大学, 印度.
- 45 个专业发展课程 ELEMENT K, USA (现在是 Skillsoft).

技术技能: Java (Core Java, Spring, Hibernate), MySQL, HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery etc.

IT 和专业证明书

- PMI-PMP®
- SCJP
- MCPD (WINDOWS, WEB)
- NCC 'B' & 'C' Certificate

奖励

- 最佳领导奖 NCC
- 最佳演说奖 NTT DATA.
- 最佳表现奖 NTT DATA.

社区服务: 管理无锡区图书馆每周英语角活动。

写双语(中英)博客:[Click Here]

语言: 印度语、英语、旁遮普语、中文、西班牙语(在学)

领英 PROFILE: [Click Here] 在线简历: [Click Here]

[Sudhir Kaushik]